Guide to the Yale University Art, Architecture, and Art History Theses and Projects
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Art, architecture, and art history theses and projects, 1915-1996; Series I
  - Fuller Daniel. Influences and Effects of Cubism upon Jacques Villon. B.F.A. 13 p., 1955 (Box 4, Folder 181)
  - Gagnon Colette [H.]. …Chaos…Ideas…Order… Solution…Acceptance…Reflection…Doubt…Rejection… M.F.A. 13 p., Slides., 1970 (Box 4, Folder 182)
  - Gaines Frances [M.] (Mrs. Henry Alsberg). El Greco, the Painter. [B.F.A.] 16 p., 1939 (Box 4, Folder 183)
  - Gallagher Michael Bedford. Soul Communication. M.F.A. 5 p. Slides., 1970 (Box 4, Folder 184)
  - Gastaldi Reno [J.]. The Waste Mould Process in Plaster Casting. B.F.A. 17 p., 1942 (Box 4, Folder 185)
  - Gentile Gloria [I.]. Child Art. [B.F.A.] 21 p., [1952?] (Box 4, Folder 186)
  - Gerbracht Robert [T.]. Egyptian Mural Procedure. B.F.A.[?]. 16 p., 1951 (Box 4, Folder 187)
  - Ghikas Panos [G.]. The Relation of Painting in the Abstract to Music. B.F.A. 11 p., 1943 (Box 4, Folder 188)
  - Ghikas Panos [G.]. A Study of the T" ao-T" ieh: Origin and Evolution on Bronzes of the Yin and Yin-Chou Periods. M.F.A. 41 p., 1947 (Box 4, Folder 189)
  - Gibson Katherine A. The Potential Position of Sculpture in Contemporary Life. [B.F.A.] 25 p., 1937 (Box 4, Folder 190)
  - Gilkison Joan [W.]. Kandinsky. B.F.A. 11 P., 1948 (Box 4, Folder 191)
  - Gillette W. Dean. A Comparison of Kandinsky and Mondrian. B.F.A. 23 p., 1954 (Box 4, Folder 192)
  - Gillette W. Dean. Mosaic Making and Notes on the Visual in Historic: Mosaics. M.F.A. 150 p., 1957 (Box 4, Folder 193)
  - Glaser Shirley Phelps. Cubism. B.F.A. 11 p., 1944 (Box 4, Folder 194)
  - Goldman, Anita. A Proposal for a Basic Design Curriculum. 25 p., undated (Box 4, Folder 195)
  - Grandy Winfred Milton. Sculpture in Relief. [B.F.A.] 11 p., 1931 (Box 4, Folder 196)
  - Gray Larry Lynn. A Discussion of my Work: 1967-1969. M.F.A. 10 p. Slides. (Box 4, Folder 197)
  - Graziani Sante. The Training of Painters from Medieval Times to the Present. B.F.A.[1943]. 14 p., 1942 (Box 4, Folder 198)
  - Graziani Sante. Wilson, Harunobu, Dürer, and Cimabue: A Comparison of Modes. M.F.A. 43 p., [1948?] (Box 4, Folder 199)
  - Greeley Benita P[ape] (Mrs. Wilder J.). An Appreciation of Gothic Tapestries [B.F.A.] 15 p., 1937 (Box 4, Folder 200)
  - Green Frank Paul. Maya Measure. M.F.A. 43 p., 1952 (Box 4, Folder 201)
  - Greenleaf Elizabeth. [Untitled portfolio]. M.F.A. 19 p., 1967 (Box 4, Folder 202)
  - Griffin Gillett G. A Discussion of Mochica Architecture. B.F.A. 13 p., 1951 (Box 4, Folder 203)
  - Grimley Madeline (Mrs. Thomas P. Elder). Art or the Artist?[B.F.A.]. 7 p., 1930 (Box 4, Folder 204)
  - Gross Cynthia Maris. Some Aspects of Symmetry and Asymmetry Based on the Cube in Relation to Three-Dimensional Form and Sculpture. B.F.A. 39 p., 1955 (Box 4, Folder 205)
  - Guidone Thomas C. Without Adequate Craftsmanship No Great Art can be Born. B.F.A. 16 p., 1947 (Box 4, Folder 206)
  - Gute Herbert J. Sport in Art. [B.F.A.]. 13 p., 1933 (Box 4, Folder 207)
  - Haber Leonard V. An Introduction to the Study of Color. B.F.A. 17 p., 1936 (Box 4, Folder 208)
  - Hardie Dougles E. A Conception of a Mural. B.F.A. 21 p., 1951 (Box 4, Folder 209)
  - Harrington Oliver W. Government Sponsored Art. B.F.A. 8 p., 1940 (Box 4, Folder 210)
  - Harris Harvey [S.]. Analysis of a Mixtec Vessel. [B.F.A.]. 12 p., [1951?] (Box 4, Folder 211)
  - Hatch John W. On Sung Painting. B.F.A. 22 p., 1948 (Box 4, Folder 212)
  - Hatch John W. Chen Jung's Dragon Scrolls: A Reconstruction. M.F.A. 71 p., 1949 (Box 4, Folder 213)
  - Hegh Hugh Edgar. The Life of the Virgin. M.F.A. 59 p., 1942 (Box 4, Folder 214)
  - Helfman Sheldon S. A Tapestry Design for the Story of Creation. B.F.A. 9 p., 1958 (Box 4, Folder 215)
  - Henderson Lagrand T. The Importance of the Abstract Qualities in Art. B.F.A. [?] 9 p., [1925?] (Box 5, Folder 216)
  - Hennington J. Floyd [Jr]. The Development of Cubism as a Source of Contemporary American Painting. M.F.A. 78 p., 1948 (Box 5, Folder 217)
  - Herpich Wayne. Shadows. M.F.A. 11 p. Slides., 1969 (Box 5, Folder 218)
  - Herstand Arnold L. An Examination of Three Scrolls from Kozanji Traditionally Attributed to Toba Sojo Kakuyu. B.F.A. 27 p., 1952 (Box 5, Folder 219)
  - Herter Christine (Mrs. William S. Kendall). Knowledge and Intuition in the Creation of Works of Art. [B.F.A.] 10 p., 1915 (Box 5, Folder 220)
  - Heun Virginia E. Carl Milles. B.F.A. 25 p., 1946 (Box 5, Folder 221)
  - Hilton John TenEyck. The Method of Aims and Means as an Index to Understanding a Cassoni in the Jarvis Collection. B.F.A. 7 p., 1941 (Box 5, Folder 222)
  - Hirsche H. Lee. Of Ships and Counterpoint. B.F.A. 28 p., 1954 (Box 5, Folder 223)
  - Hitchcock Suzanne G. (Mrs. Robert L. clothier Jr.). Dunoyer di Segonzag. B.F.A. 9 p., 1944 (Box 5, Folder 224)
  - Hodge G. Stuart. Picasso. B.F.A. 13 p., 1941 (Box 5, Folder 225)
  - Hoener Arthur. Two Technical Studies: Photo chemical and Solvent Reaction of Drying Oils, and Plastic Tempera Mediums, M.F.A. 96 p., 1958 (Box 5, Folder 226)
  - Hogfeldt Aage Victor. The Common Spirit of the Art of Certain Modern Painters, Children, and Primitive Peoples. B.F.A. 17 p., 1951 (Box 5, Folder 227)
  - Hovsepian Leon. The Masters [sic] Works compared with the works of his Formative Period. B.F.A. 16 p., 1941 (Box 5, Folder 228)
  - Howard Mary C. (Mrs. Wilmer A. Jennings). Creative Tendencies in Contemporary American Art. [B.F.A.]. 10 p., [1935?] (Box 5, Folder 229)
  - Hubbard Mary Alice (Mrs. Clark L. Stevens). The Work of Piero Della Francesca and its Relation to the Universal Spirit of Art B.F.A. 29 p., 1928 (Box 5, Folder 230)
  - Hudson Kenneth Eugene. Art and Man's Daily Life. B.F.A. 12 p., 1927 (Box 5, Folder 231)
  - Hull Jessie G. (Mrs. Henrick M. Mayer),. Symbolism in Art. [B.F.A.]. 10 p., 1932 (Box 5, Folder 232)
  - Hult Bernard E. Egyptian Painting in the Old Kingdom. B.F.A. 18 p., 1948 (Box 5, Folder 233)
  - Hupalowsky J[oseph]. A Psychological Aspect of Perception and its Relation to Art. B.F.A. 10 p., 1952 (Box 5, Folder 234)
  - Hutchins Maude Phelps. Michael Angelo, Sculptor. [B.F.A.] 8 p., 1926 (Box 5, Folder 235)
  - Huthsteiner George. [Photograph]., 1969 (Box 5, Folder 236)
  - Isquith Ben. Conceptions of Pictorial Space in Different Cultures. B.F.A. 11 p., 1951 (Box 5, Folder 237)
  - Jackson A[lexander] B. Jr. The Element of Humor in Painting. B.F.A. 25 p, 1953 (Box 5, Folder 238)
  - Jackson Al[exander] B. Jr. Educational Toys. M.F.A. 32 p., 1955 (Box 5, Folder 239)
  - Jackson Burt L. The Symbolism of Gold. B.F.A. 14 p., 1952 (Box 5, Folder 240)
  - Jacobson Nathaniel J. Distortion of Form in Modern Painting. B.F.A. 11 p., 1941 (Box 5, Folder 241)
  - Jagel John. A Study of Two Early Chinese Paintings. B.F.A. 52 p., 1956 (Box 5, Folder 242)
  - James Douglas Stewart. Deep Feeling. M.F.A. 15 p. Slides., 1970 (Box 5, Folder 243)
  - Johnson Tom L. Art and its Relation to America. [B.F.A.]. 15p., 1923 (Box 5, Folder 244)
  - Johnson Victor. In Pursuit of a Medium. M.F.A. 6 p. Slides., 1967 (Box 5, Folder 245)
  - Joondeph Norman [P.]. Personality and Environment in Art. B.F.A. 13 p., 1942 (Box 5, Folder 246)
  - Kabak Robert. Baroque Space. M.F.A. 55 p., 1954 (Box 5, Folder 247)
  - Kacir Charles S. The Midwestern Guilt Complex M.F.A. 8 p. Slides., 1966 (Box 5, Folder 248)
  - Kadish Daniel [M.]. A Personal Examination and Analysis of the Development of my Work at Yale. [B.F.A.]. 9 p., 1969 (Box 5, Folder 249)
  - Kammerer Herbert Lewis. Representation and Formalization in Greek Sculpture. B.F.A. 13 p., 1941 (Box 5, Folder 250)
  - Kark M[iriam] N. Child Art. M.F.A. 19 p., 1944 (Box 5, Folder 251)
  - Karmen Edward F. On the Practice of Tempera Painting. B.F.A. 14 p., 1954 (Box 5, Folder 252)
  - Kasper Edward Joseph. A Survey of Early Italian Drawing. B.F.A. 15 p., 1945 (Box 5, Folder 253)
  - Kay Bryan Conwell. On Drawing, Painting and Printmaking. M.F.A. 10 p. Slides., 1970 (Box 5, Folder 254)
  - Kazlov Brian. Gullible's Travail and the Contemporary Conceptual Credability [sic] Gap. M.F.A. 22 p. Slides., 1968 (Box 5, Folder 255)
  - Kearl, Stanley Brandon. Prehistoric Art of the Upper Paleolithic Period. M.F.A. 54 p., 1942 (Box 5, Folder 256)
  - Kells Frances. Sculpture Eclipsed. B.F.A. 24 p., 1947 (Box 5, Folder 257)
  - Kelsey Stephen Michael. Tjitjalengka. Rantja èkèk. M.F.A. 23 p. Slides., 1968 (Box 5, Folder 258)
  - Kikuchi Kenichi [K.]. The General Development of Japanese Gardens and their Probable Influence on the Reliefs Created by Isamu Noguchi. B.F.A. 16 p., 1953 (Box 5, Folder 259)
  - King Marcia E. A Consideration of the Visual and Structural Aspects Involved in the Support of the Horizontal Plane. B.F.A. 46 p., 1956 (Box 5, Folder 260)
  - Kingman Eugene. Photography in Modern Art. [B.F.A.]. 10 p., 1935 (Box 5, Folder 261)
  - Kitchen Elizabeth [S.] (Mrs. Benjamin F. Jr.). The Influence of Syndicate Art on Government Subsidized Murals in the United States. M.F.A. 93 p., 1948 (Box 5, Folder 262)
  - Kitt Charles Norman. The Works of Albrecht Dürer. B.F.A. 13 p., 1944 (Box 5, Folder 263)
  - Kliros Theodore. Child Art. B.F.A. 34 p., 1954 (Box 5, Folder 264)
  - Kliros Theodore. Creative Processes in Abstract Expressionism: A Study in a Time Complex. M.F.A. 56 p., 1956 (Box 5, Folder 265)
  - Klix Richard H. Color Theorists of the Nineteenth Century. B.F.A. 15 p., 1952 (Box 5, Folder 266)
  - Kloszewski E[ugene] [P.]. Mural Painting in Relation to Architecture. B.F.A. 21 p., 1951 (Box 5, Folder 267)
  - Koch Arthur Paul. The Art Spirit. B.F.A. 10 p., 1927 (Box 5, Folder 268)
  - Kolb William W. My Work in Systems and Computer Drawing. M.F.A.7 p., 1969 (Box 5, Folder 269)
  - Kord Victor. Encaustic Techniques. B.F.A. 13 p., 1958 (Box 6, Folder 270)
  - Kozlowski Edward Charles. Architectural Lettering: A Visual Problem. B.F.A. 33 p., 1954 (Box 6, Folder 271)
  - Kratina [K.] George. [Untitled]. [B.F.A.]. 22 p., 1937 (Box 6, Folder 272)
  - Krukowski Lucian. The Interaction of Physical Dimension and Surface Quality in the Perception of Three Dimensional Form. B.F.A. 24 p., 1955 (Box 6, Folder 273)
  - Kukes Roger. Thesis Project. M.F.A. 27 p. Slides., 1967 (Box 6, Folder 274)
  - Kulaway Ronald. Esthetic Theories of Analytical Cubism. B.F.A. 24 p., 1955 (Box 6, Folder 275)
  - Kupferman Nancy. A Thesis. M.F.A. 6 p. Slides., 1968 (Box 6, Folder 276)
  - Kuziel Frank [J.]. The Biography of Peter Paul Rubens. [B.F.A.]. 14 p., 1943 (Box 6, Folder 277)
  - Lam Jennette Brinsmade (Mrs. George L.). The Evolution of Collage. B.F.A. 37 p., 1954 (Box 6, Folder 278)
  - Landis Judi. The Landiscape. M.F.A. 7 p., 1970 (Box 6, Folder 279)
  - Lang Karl W. Bauhaus. B.F.A. 7 p., 1951 (Box 6, Folder 280)
  - Larrick Danny D. [Untitled portfolio] M.F.A. 17 P., 1969 (Box 6, Folder 281)
  - Larsen Marie. The Art of Antoine Watteau. B.F.A. 16 p., 1943 (Box 6, Folder 282)
  - Larsson Anna-Greta. The Integration of Fine Art and Advertising B.F.A. 19 p., 1944 (Box 6, Folder 283)
  - Le Blanc Lloyd. [Untitled portfolio]. M.F.A. 44 p., 1967 (Box 6, Folder 284-285)
  - Lederer Bertha Van Buren. The Culmination of Sienese Art in the Work of Simone Martini. B.F.A. 8 p., 1935 (Box 6, Folder 286)
  - Leet Glen F., Jr.,. Dear Prudence. M.F.A. 8 p. Slides., 1970 (Box 6, Folder 287)
  - Leete William W. Factors Distinguishing the Figure from the Ground in Painting. B.F.A. 38 p., 1955 (Box 6, Folder 288)
  - Leete William W. Color Plasticity. [M.F.A.] 41 p., 1957 (Box 6, Folder 289)
  - Leggett William A. Color and Techniques in Industrial Design. B.F.A. 9 p., 1951 (Box 6, Folder 290)
  - Leonardi Hector J. Humor and Wit in Twentieth Century Painting. M.F.A. 49p., 1955 (Box 6, Folder 291)
  - Lerner Judith. [Untitled]. M.F.A. 6 p. Slides., 1970 (Box 6, Folder 292)
  - Lettick. Birney Alexander,. Honoré Daumier. B.F.A. 21 p., 1942 (Box 6, Folder 293)
  - Levers Robert [L.]. An Outline of the Historical Development of Picasso's Art. B.F.A. 12 p., 1952 (Box 6, Folder 294)
  - Levine Saul. The Historical Role of the Isms in Painting. [B.F.A.] 13 p., 1938 (Box 6, Folder 295)
  - Levinson J[esse]. Comedy in the Work of Paul Klee. B.F.A. 45 p., 1953 (Box 6, Folder 296)
  - Lewis Arne Martin. Croce's Intuition. B.F.A. 25 p., 1954 (Box 6, Folder 297)
  - Lewis C. Stanley. [Untitled portfolio] M.F.A. 29 p., 1966 (Box 6, Folder 298)
  - Leydenfrost Robert J. An Approach to Today. B.F.A. 14 p., 1951 (Box 6, Folder 299)
  - Liguori Victor. The Role of Intentionality in the Creative Process: An Inquiry into the Way Cognitive Union is Realized in the Experience of the Artist. M.F.A. 56 p., 1956 (Box 6, Folder 300)
  - Linder Ronald H. Insights toward the Understanding of my Work. M.F.A. 22 p. Portfolio, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 301)
  - Lloyd George O. Notes on my Painting. M.F.A. 5 p. Slides., 1969 (Box 6, Folder 302)
  - Lo Monaco Louis Frank. An Investigation in the Field of Color Etching. B.F.A. 19 p., 1957 (Box 6, Folder 303)
  - Loomis Dana A. Cubism B.F.A. 20 p., 1951 (Box 6, Folder 304)
  - Loomis Henry Luther. The Yale years M.F.A. 10 p. Slides., 1968 (Box 6, Folder 305)
  - Lorenzini Eldora Pauline. Andrea Mantegna. B.F.A. 17 p., 1944 (Box 6, Folder 306)
  - Lorenzini Eldora Pauline. The Revival of Surrealism in Painting. M.F.A. 89 p., 1945 (Box 6, Folder 307)
  - Lourie Herbert Solomon. The Bonampak Murals (Room #1) M.F.A.32 p., 1951 (Box 6, Folder 308)
  - Lucca Joseph S. The Bodoni Type Face. M.F.A. 38 p., 1956 (Box 6, Folder 309)
  - Lukosius Richard B. Modern Glass. B.F.A. 7 p., 1948 (Box 6, Folder 310)
  - Lyon George Cecil. Pablo Picasso Ruiz. B.F.A. 13 p., 1941 (Box 6, Folder 311)
  - Lytle Richard. The Development of a Triform Inspired by Dante's Divine Comedy. B.F.A. 37 p. Portfolio, 1957 (Box 6, Folder 312)
  - McCormick Robert [J.]. Fiorenzo di Lorenzo. [B.F.A.] 12 p., 1936 (Box 6, Folder 313)
  - McCracken William Chave. Seurat: A Reconsideration of his work. [B.A. (1943)]. 127 p., 1942 (Box 6, Folder 314)
  - McCracken William Wier Miskimmon. A Few Examples of Cycles of Taste in Art of the Public and the Influence of Such on the Artist. B.F.A. 12 p., 1931 (Box 6, Folder 315)
  - McCullough Joseph Warren. Some Attitudes and Opinions and the Resultant Uses of Color. M.F.A. 46 p., 1951 (Box 6, Folder 316)
  - Mach John Joseph. Gold in Manuscript Illumination. B.F.A. 17 p., 1945 (Box 7, Folder 317)
  - MacLennan Mary E. Modern Glass and Its Decorative Uses.[B.F.A.]. 8 p., 1943 (Box 7, Folder 318)
  - Maconachy Henry D. After the Art School [B.F.A.]. 10 p., 1928 (Box 7, Folder 319)
  - McVeigh Maude Phelps
    See: box 5, folder 235
  - Maisel Jay N. A Paper Concerning the Effect of Religion and Culture on the Formal Aspects of Primitive Negro Sculpture. B.F.A. 50 p., 1953 (Box 7, Folder 320)
  - Majewski Laurence James. Some Observations in the Conservation of Works of Art M.F.A. 54 p., 1954 (Box 7, Folder 321)
  - Malone Robert A. An Inquiry into the Nature of the Aesthetic Experience B.F.A. [1952] 11 p., 1951 (Box 7, Folder 322)
  - Mandel William H. Painting in Modern Architecture. B.F.A. 14 p., 1953 (Box 7, Folder 323)
  - Marchese John Sebastian. An Analytical Criticism of the Contemporary Artist. B.F.A. 9 p., 1943 (Box 7, Folder 324)
  - Marcus Marilyn. Cezannes [sic] Water Colors B.F.A. 43 p., 1952 (Box 7, Folder 325)
  - Marcus Nina. Planning versus Creation in my work. M.F.A. 6 p., 1969 (Box 7, Folder 326)
  - Markman Ronald. A Sense of Nonsense in Art B.F.A. 51 p., 1957 (Box 7, Folder 327-379)
  - Marossi Ruth. Symbolism and Art: An Analysis of the Writings of Susanne K. Langer and Charles K. Ogden. B.F.A. 25 p., 1954 (Box 7, Folder 330)
  - Marriott William Allen. Concerning my work: 1965-1967 M.F.A. 8 p. Slides. (Box 7, Folder 331)
  - Marshall Alice. [Untitled portfolio]. M.F.A. 14 p., 1965 (Box 7, Folder 332)
  - Martin Willa Gray. The Grotesque in Christian Art. [B.F.A.].16 p., 1936 (Box 7, Folder 333)
  - Matsumoto Georgia. A Personal Essay on my work M.F.A. 13 p. Slides., 1968 (Box 7, Folder 334)
  - Matt John. The Progression of my Sculptural Ideas 1965-1968. M.F.A. 21 p. Portfolio. (Box 7, Folder 335)
  - Matz Elisabeth. Pen Drawing B.F.A. 13 p., undated (Box 7, Folder 336)
  - Maxim Doris. Fresco Painting [B.F.A.] 16 p., 1940 (Box 7, Folder 337)
  - Meinke Henry J. Frontality in Piero Della Francesca's Work B.F.A. 11 p., 1932 (Box 7, Folder 338)
  - Melendy Barbara. Paul Cezanne B.F.A. 10 p., 1941 (Box 7, Folder 339)
  - Melson Holland Roberts. The Early Work of Alvin Lustig 1937-1943. M.F.A. 16 P., 1958 (Box 7, Folder 340)
  - Menconi Ralph [J.]. An Inquiry into Modern Sculpture B.F A. 15 p., 1939 (Box 7, Folder 341)
  - Messer Clarissa. Cubism and Modern Architecture: And their Use of Space B.F.A.15 p., 1943 (Box 7, Folder 342)
  - Meyer Philip S. [Untitled portfolio] M.F.A. 15 p., 1965 (Box 7, Folder 343)
  - Michalczyk Casimir. Pattern and Structure in Sculpture B.F.A. 9 p., 1940 (Box 7, Folder 344)
  - Milici Salvatore M.
    See: box 10, folder 541
  - Mills George V. The Progress of American Sculpture as Exemplified in Various Expositions of the United States. B F.A. 31 p., 1937 (Box 7, Folder 345)
  - Milton Peter W. Kandinski and the Organic Theory. B.F.A. 43 p., 1954 (Box 7, Folder 346)
  - Missal Paul. [Untitled] M.F.A. 6 p. Slides., 1967 (Box 7, Folder 347)
  - Mittell Carl Eugene. Realistic Representation in Florentine Art. [B.F A.] 10 p., 1931 (Box 7, Folder 348)
  - Moore John J. [Untitled] M.F.A. 8 p. Slides, 1968 (Box 7, Folder 349)
  - Moore Julius M. Jehan Foucquet [B.F.A.] 11 p., 1938 (Box 7, Folder 350)
  - Morley Marjorie Elizabeth. Appreciation of Sculptural Composition B.F.A. 19 p., 1939 (Box 7, Folder 351)
  - Morris Edward Donald. Drapery in Painting: A Discussion Based on Examples from the Work of the Byzantine Period, Giotto, Carlo Crivelli, and Dürer. B.F.A. 19 p., 1945 (Box 7, Folder 352)
  - Morris F. Michael. Three-Dimensional Disorientation M.F.A. 23 p. Portfolio., 1967 (Box 7, Folder 353)
  - Moskal Kathleen [A.]. Painting Thesis. M.F.A. 8 p. Slides., [1969?] (Box 7, Folder 354)
  - Mosman Warren T. The Return of Sculpture to Architecture? B.F.A. 10 p., 1930 (Box 7, Folder 355)
  - Moylan Katherine z. Antonione Bourdelle: Sculptor, Poet and Philosopher B.F.A. 12 p., 1931 (Box 7, Folder 356)
  - Mulliken Eleanor. Gardens and Garden Sculpture B.F.A. 10 p., 1936 (Box 7, Folder 357)
  - Murata Nancy Silvia. Remarks on my Painting M.F.A. 7 p Slides, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 358)
  - Murphy Charles E. Experiments with the Color Photogram B.F.A. 17 p., 1958 (Box 7, Folder 359)
  - Mutz Tisdale Lawrence. A Painting Treatise about Sandro Botticelli B.F.A. 17 p, 1939 (Box 7, Folder 360)
  - Myers Amy [G.]. Paul Klee B.F.A. 24 p., 1952 (Box 7, Folder 361)
  - Newell Frances Read. A Future for American Art B.F.A. 8 p., 1940 (Box 7, Folder 362)
  - Nicholas Vivian. The Influence of the Orient on Western Art [B.F.A.] 9 p., 1936 (Box 7, Folder 363)
  - Nichols Elliot S. Jr. Investigations into the Form and Meaning of Turner"s Compositions B.F.A. 42 p., 1957 (Box 7, Folder 364)
  - Nicholson Emrich. The Renaissance and Today [B.F.A.] 13 p., 1936 (Box 7, Folder 365)
  - North Lois. The Reconstruction of the Nike of Doura-Europos and Graeco-Parthian Painting in General B.F.A. 13 p., 1930 (Box 7, Folder 366)
  - Oberle Roger Alan. Landscape Thesis. M.F.A. 8 p. Slides., 1968 (Box 7, Folder 367)
  - O"Connell Hilda. [Untitled] M.F.A. 11 p. Slides, 1969 (Box 7, Folder 368)
  - Offner Elliot M. The Nature of Childrens [sic] Painting in the Four, Five, and Six Year Age Group. B.F.A. 18 p., 1953 (Box 7, Folder 369)
  - Ohlms Hugo. Early Christian and Byzantine Art B.F.A. 24 p., 1933 (Box 7, Folder 370)
  - Pacelli Vincent. Thesis on Stained Glass [B.F.A.] 8 p., 1938 (Box 7, Folder 371)
  - Pacelli William Gaetano. Casting B.F.A. 13 p., 1948 (Box 7, Folder 372)
  - Paier Edward Theodore Jr. Peter Breugel the Elder B.F.A. 14 p., 1941 (Box 7, Folder 373)
  - Pappas Mitchel Nicholas. Modern Mexicans B.F.A. 15 p., 1941 (Box 7, Folder 374)
  - Pappas Mitchel Nicholas. The Technique of Buon-Fresco M.F.A.[1948] 51 p., 1947 (Box 7, Folder 375)
  - Parker Ann Russell. The Esthetic Use of the Functional Properties of Photography B.F.A. 75 p., 1956 (Box 7, Folder 376-377)
  - Parker Patricia. Perceptual Characteristics of Line Examined in Relation to Selected Compositions by Cezanne. B.F.A. 39 p., 1955 (Box 7, Folder 378)
  - Parrino George. Notes M.F.A. 42 p. Slides., 1970 (Box 7, Folder 379)
  - Patterson Dorothea. Chinese Painting in the T"ang Dynasty [B.F.A.] 10 p., 1936 (Box 7, Folder 380)
  - Pattison Abbott Lawrence. Art and Beauty B.F.A. 11 p., 1939 (Box 7, Folder 381)
  - Paul Daniel A. [Untitled]. M.F.A. 5 p. Slides., 1967 (Box 7, Folder 382)
  - Pease Raymond [S.]. Paolo Uccello B.F.A. 10 p., 1933 (Box 7, Folder 383)
  - Perlmutter Julius. The Four Seasons: A Study in Depiction in Fresco. B.F.A. 63 p., 1957 (Box 8, Folder 384)
  - Petryn Andrew Fred. Gold Work B.F.A. 20 p., 1943 (Box 8, Folder 385)
  - Pierson William Harvey Jr. The Minoan Frescoes at Knossos. M.F.A. 32 p., 1936 (Box 8, Folder 386)
  - Pindell Howardena Doreen. Problems Encountered and Posed in my Development as a Painter M.F.A. 9 p. Slides, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 387)
  - Piskoti James. [Untitled] M.F.A. 15 p.Slides., 1969 (Box 8, Folder 388)
  - Pleason Morris. The Educational Value of Medieval Sculpture. B.F.A. 22 p., 1932 (Box 8, Folder 389)
  - Popolizio Vincent J. The Symphonic Structure of the Far Eastern Hand Scroll as Exemplified in Sesschu's [sic] Spring and Autumn Land-scape M.F.A. 24 p., 1948 (Box 8, Folder 390)
  - Prevo George J. Direction B.F.A. 7 p., 1951 (Box 8, Folder 391)
  - Prince Stephanie. An Analysis of Northern European Art. B.F.A. 17 p., 1936 (Box 8, Folder 392)
  - Przepiorka Emil James. Tintoretto: Jacopo Robusti, 1518-1594. 11 p., 1939 (Box 8, Folder 393)
  - Pullman [James] Chris[topher]. Problem: Develop a Comprehensive Signing Program for the Yale School of Art and Architecture.[B.F.A.? M.F.A.?] 15 p., 1966 (Box 8, Folder 394)
  - Quackenbush David S. Mont-Saint-Michel, Normandy B.F.A. 28 p., 1951 (Box 8, Folder 395)
  - Quackenbush David S. William Caxton, The First English Printer, his Life and Production. M.F.A. 70 p., 1954 (Box 8, Folder 396)
  - Qually Ingolf J. Progress and Art. B.F.A. 13 p., 1942 (Box 8, Folder 397)
  - Qually Ingolf J. Painting in Egg Tempera. M.F.A., 42 p., 1947 (Box 8, Folder 398)
  - Rabinowitz Harold W. A Study of Space Concepts in the 20th Century. B.F.A. 48 p., 1951 (Box 8, Folder 399)
  - Rabinowitz Harold W. A Painter's Approach to Growth-Forms in Nature. M.F.A. 46 p., 1954 (Box 8, Folder 400)
  - Radomski Alphonse F. Painting of Carlo Crivelli. B.F.A. 11 p., 1947 (Box 8, Folder 401)
  - Raffaele Joseph H. The Hand-made Book of Calligraphy. B.F.A. 22 p., 1956 (Box 8, Folder 402)
  - Randall T[heodore] A. Formal Beauty. B.F.A. 10 p., 1938 (Box 8, Folder 403)
  - Reardon Mary A. The Painters [sic] Palette of Materials; Decorative Media of the Present Day. B.F.A. 26 p., 1938 (Box 8, Folder 404)
  - Reid Sylvia. Research and Experiments in the Use of Polymer Tempera Medium. B.F.A. 26 p., 1955 (Box 8, Folder 405)
  - Revenson Maxwell. The Desirability of Collaboration between the Architect, Painter, and Sculptor at the Primary Level of Design. B.F.A. 20 p., 1951 (Box 8, Folder 406)
  - Reynolds Douglas W. Psyho-analysis of Piero di Cosimo. B.F.A. 15 p., 1941 (Box 8, Folder 407)
  - Reynolds James M. A Comparison of the View points that Produced Murals in the Italian Renaissance and Tang China. B.F.A. 45 p., 1951 (Box 8, Folder 408)
  - Richardson Terrance A. [Untitled]. M.F.A. 4 p. Slides., 1967 (Box 8, Folder 409)
  - Richmond G[aylord] D. Leonardo da. Vinci. B.F.A.12 p., 1931 (Box 8, Folder 410)